<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DAZ codes Blog</title>
    <link>/blog</link>
    <description>My thoughts about coding and anything else</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:17:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025</title>
      <link>/blog/advent-of-code-2025</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/advent-of-code-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>I&apos;d never heard of Advent of Code before I joined Yozu, so this was the second time I had taken part in trying to complete the challenges. Last year I achieved 42/50 of the stars available.

The 2025 Advent of Code changed the format a little bit from the year before. There were only 12 days of chal...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Number Methods</title>
      <link>/blog/ruby-number-methods</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/ruby-number-methods</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>One of the biggest advantages of making the [Ruby Monkey](/projects/ruby-monkey) library was going through all of the Ruby methods for numbers, strings, arrays and hashes. I learnt about so many methods I had no idea existed and discovered some really useful ones. In this post I&apos;m going to look at s...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Template to Func</title>
      <link>/blog/template-to-func</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/template-to-func</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Yesterday at work, somebody posted this JavaScript snippet, saying they liked how the `some` method worked:

```javascript
const anyChecked = filterTargets.some(filter =&gt; filter.checked)
````

Someone replied, saying they preferred how to do it in Ruby:

```ruby
any_checked = filter_targets.any?(&amp;:c...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Changed To A Career In Software Development</title>
      <link>/blog/career-change</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/career-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>At the start of 2024 I decided to change careers. After over 20 years teaching maths and computer science I decided to turn my passion into a profession and become a software developer. I had always loved coding and enjoyed teaching it, but was finding my hobby more fun than my day job and wanted to...</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>